Now we're moving into executing the
project to deliver business value.
So we are moving into
executing process group
if you're referring back
to that process map.
All right, this is where we're doing the
work of the project.
So we would have planned, had agreed upon
the scope with our stakeholders.
They would have agreed upon the scope
based and signed off.
Based on that scope,
we figure out how long
it'll take, how much it's going to cost.
What's going to cost us, the resources.
Okay, so we would be
baseline before we move
into executing to do
the work of the project.
All right.
Now, that's what the predictive.
If we look at the second slide,
executing the project to deliver business
value is equivalent to direct
and manage the project
work process, where the
work will actually be done.
to create our deliverables also approved
change requests will actually be
implemented here as well all right as
we're doing the work of the project we
will also create work performance data
these are your called raw observations of
measurements taken during executing as
we're doing the work of the project these
are our actuals like number of change
requests number of validations validation
cycles, actual costs, actual start dates,
actual finish dates, percent complete,
for example.
That is data, actuals
taken during executing
as we're doing the work of the project.
You'll see later when we talk about
monitoring and controlling.
It will compare our plan, our baselines,
what was agreed upon, to the data.
We'll be looking for variants so we can
quickly take action.
all right so we are delivering business
value here so as we're doing the work of
the project we're supposed to instill a
sense of urgency in the team of course to
deliver value as quickly as possible as
early as possible all right so business
value itself is a quantifiable benefit
derived from the business endeavor or the
project remember we
had the business case and
the benefits management plan that came in.
We had a reason for the
project and it was stated how
the project is supposed
to benefit the organization.
All right.
So that includes financial, whether it's
making money or saving money.
Also, improving processes that can help
expedite processes or creating new
processes, increasing
market share, promoting
goodwill, all those things
we discussed before.
that were inputs to develop
our project charter that
was used to develop our
project management plan.
All right.
So business value absolutely could be
incrementally delivered.
We usually don't deliver business value
day one.
For example, it's going to take us a
minute to create our deliverables.
Let's look at the next slide.
So in Agile, business value is huge.
Okay.
And well, not that it is an
predictive but the goal is
to deliver about business
value as early as possible.
That's the agile goal.
All right.
So to do so we see on this slide minimum
viable product MVP.
That is the smallest collection
of features that can be
included in a product for
customers to consider it functional.
So for example, car, a basic bear.
bones car you have you know a little box
you know it's not even metal anymore
whatever cars are made of now you've got
some four wheels you've got the shell of
the car basic seats no AC nothing extra
okay that's a minimum viable product MVP
all right we will that's the minimum that
customer sees is actually of use.
What we will do later, and you'll see in
the business minimum business increment,
I'm skipping a bullet.
That's the smallest amount of value that
could be added to a product or service
that will benefit the business, meaning a
customer is actually
going to purchase that car.
Okay?
We also have that second bullet,
m mf minimum marketable feature smallest
unit of functionality that provides
tangible value to customers so an example
of that you add on to the car like having
some AC having a next increment is
something that the customers would buy
having reclining seats you know for
example all right We will
use as tools and techniques,
the project management
information system, PMIS.
All our project information is coming in
and out of PMIS.
Remember, that's an EEF, enterprise
environmental factor.
It's also a tool and technique that we
use.
We will use that information system.
So it will include change control,
how changes will be made on our project,
the processes and procedures needed.
It will also include configuration
management system, processes, procedures
for version control, making sure,
again, that we're always working from the
latest plans, documents, baselines,
versions, all right, our reporting
systems, data storage
systems, how we'll archive,
distribute project information
from these systems.
I will track details
and any software tools,
manual tools that we will
use to manage a project.
So yeah, it might not always
be automated, but these are
all different tools that we will
use to manage our projects.